<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vegan Talk on Veggie Guide</title>
    <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/categories/vegan-talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vegan Talk on Veggie Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veggieguide.co.uk/categories/vegan-talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is it okay for vegans to eat animals which died naturally?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/is-it-okay-for-vegans-to-eat-animals-which-died-naturally/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/is-it-okay-for-vegans-to-eat-animals-which-died-naturally/</guid>
      <description>This is a question I like to call a ‘vegan loophole’: a hypothetical and likely improbable question raised in order to challenge vegan ethics. Other loopholes include ‘if you were on a desert island…?’ and “What if you were living in Siberia…?”
What are we really asking here? Every vegan will have experienced some version of the ‘vegan loophole’ and will more than likely have asked something similar themselves before making the switch to veganism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are We Ashamed To Be Vegan?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/are-we-ashamed-to-be-vegan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:06:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/are-we-ashamed-to-be-vegan/</guid>
      <description>Vegan, by definition, describes ‘a person who does not eat or use animal products’. But in reality, the word holds negative connotations. Whether you’re a lifelong vegan or devout meat eater, you’ve probably heard vegans variously referred to as hippies, tree-huggers, deranged, ill, pushy, anorexic, extreme or obnoxious. What the word doesn’t immediately suggest is compassionate, loving, kind, supportive or well intended.
Like many others who have chosen to adopt the vegan lifestyle, I have experienced first hand the backlash of the ‘vegan stereotype’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Force Veganism on Your Kids!… What’s Your View?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/dont-force-veganism-on-your-kids-whats-your-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 13:10:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/dont-force-veganism-on-your-kids-whats-your-view/</guid>
      <description>I have always been firmly in the: “You shouldn’t force your beliefs onto your children”, camp and until recently, this even included veganism. However, a few things have begun to change my mind.
The power of conversation The other day I was discussing veganism with a friend who has been mostly vegetarian since childhood and has recently begun to embrace a more plant-based diet. This one conversation was the root of the change in my perception of raising vegan children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doubting Veganism? Maybe You Should!</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/doubting-veganism-maybe-you-should/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 18:40:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/doubting-veganism-maybe-you-should/</guid>
      <description>A vegan diet is sometimes regarded as ‘extreme’ and is often lumped with popular ‘fad’ diets. Cutting out animal products from your diet raises many questions from onlookers regarding your health.
Many people in the UK  (around 542,000 according to The Vegan Society  ) follow a vegan/plant-based diet. So, with numbers ever increasing, can plant-based eating be sustained and still provide everything we need to be healthy?
With new year campaigns such as Veganuary  , this is the month where interests peak and the amount of people following a plant-based diet takes a boost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Top 7 Ways to be a Better Vegan have Nothing to do with Animals!</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-top-7-ways-to-be-a-better-vegan-have-nothing-to-do-with-animals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-top-7-ways-to-be-a-better-vegan-have-nothing-to-do-with-animals/</guid>
      <description>Avoiding animal products is not only the most important factor in being a vegan, it is the definition. But going plant-based and wearing hemp should not be where you complete your ethical evolution. Below are my top tips for being a better, more effective vegan:
1 – First rule of Veganism… “Don’t talk about Veganism!” OK, this one’s controversial I know, but I feel it needs addressing. It doesn’t take long before your friends and colleagues find out that you’ve gone vegan, so there is, arguably, no need to openly push it on people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There’s No Real Difference Between Meat Eaters and Vegans</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/theres-no-real-difference-between-meat-eaters-and-vegans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/theres-no-real-difference-between-meat-eaters-and-vegans/</guid>
      <description>Here at Veggie Guide, we love people just as much as we love animals and we love meat eaters just as much as veggies and vegans. Why?
Because deep down we all have a lot in common.
Let me explain…
1 – We are weak! I used to eat meat (I ate meat for 24 years), then one day, when I no longer felt I needed it, I stopped.
Several years later The same happened for milk, some time after it was cheese, then finally eggs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
