<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emily Stevenson on Veggie Guide</title>
    <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/emily-stevenson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emily Stevenson on Veggie Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:20:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/emily-stevenson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Avocado Spaghetti with Roasted Asparagus and Vine Tomatoes</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-avocado-spaghetti-with-roasted-asparagus-and-vine-tomatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:20:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-avocado-spaghetti-with-roasted-asparagus-and-vine-tomatoes/</guid>
      <description>A great weekday dinner when you don’t have much time to spare but want a filling and nutritious dinner. The spaghetti is served with English asparagus and tomatoes on the vine, however these can easily be replaced with other vegetables you have in your fridge — such as roasted broccoli, peppers or mushrooms.
This recipe serves 3
Ingredients:  300g wholemeal spaghetti Roughly 12-16 tomatoes on the vine, or 3 handfuls of cherry tomatoes 10-15 asparagus stems 1-2 tbsp olive oil 3 handfuls of spinach Sea salt  For the sauce:  1 large avocado 2 tbsp soya coconut yoghurt 200-300ml coconut milk Juice of 1/2 lemon 1 tbsp olive oil 2 garlic cloves  Method: Boil a pan of water and cook the spaghetti according to the instructions on the packet (this may vary).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Banana Mango &amp; Tahini Smoothie Bowl</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-banana-mango-and-tahini-smoothie-bowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 13:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-banana-mango-and-tahini-smoothie-bowl/</guid>
      <description>This nutritious snack is delicious, especially on a lovely sunny morning, and will keep you filled up until lunchtime. Don’t like banana or mango? You can swap these with any other type of frozen fruit — adapt the toppings to your preference.
This recipe serves 1
Ingredients:  1 frozen banana (freeze in small chunks the night before) 80g frozen mango chunks (roughly one handful) 2 medjool dates with the pips removed 1 tbsp tahini 1 tbsp coconut soya yoghurt 200ml plant-based milk  Toppings (optional): 1 tbsp peanut butter, a handful of granola, a sprinkle of seeds and cacao nibs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Sweet Potato and Chickpea Patties</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-sweet-potato-and-chickpea-patties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 08:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-sweet-potato-and-chickpea-patties/</guid>
      <description>A hearty, satisfying meal when you want something comforting and filling. These tasty sweet potato and chickpea patties are also great to have as left overs in a salad the next day. The nutritious patties are easy to make and require minimal preparation.
This recipe makes 3-4 patties.
Ingredients:  1 tin drained chickpeas 1 sweet potato, peeled, chopped into chunks and well boiled 1/2 chopped red onion 1 tsp oregano 1 tsp cumin 1/2 tsp garlic granules Pinch of salt and pepper Small handful of flour 1-2 tbsp olive oil  To serve:  Wholemeal buns Slices of avocado Spoonful of hummus Fresh spinach  Method:  Boil the sweet potato for around 15min (until soft inside — check with a fork) and drain, add to a mixing bowl and also add the drained chickpeas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
