<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John Bogumsky on Veggie Guide</title>
    <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/john-bogumsky/</link>
    <description>Recent content in John Bogumsky on Veggie Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/john-bogumsky/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>5 Top Tips to Growing Veggies for Beginners</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/5-top-tips-to-growing-veggies-for-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/5-top-tips-to-growing-veggies-for-beginners/</guid>
      <description>Many would agree, supermarkets are convenient, but it’s nice to know where your food comes from and incredibly satisfying to know you grew it yourself. We asked John Bogumsky, a Leicester born allotment owner, for his top tips on how to get started growing your own vegetables.
I remember visiting my granddads allotment as a boy. To me and my sister it was a magical kingdom. It was full of home-made greenhouses and sheds made of old pallets and disused buildings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grow Your Own Veggies: Read About Gardening</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/grow-your-own-veggies-read-about-gardening/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 14:38:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/grow-your-own-veggies-read-about-gardening/</guid>
      <description>To successfully grow vegetables and fruit, it is important to read about all aspects of gardening. Once you have started, you will gain valuable experience in both what to do and what not to do.
There are four main areas you could gain the necessary knowledge, these are: books, social media, websites, and magazines.
Books Books are a great source of knowledge as as the depth of information far outweighs other sources and each book mentioned below is highly regarded by experienced gardeners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grow Your Own Veggies: Finding the Right Plot</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/grow-your-own-veggies-finding-the-right-plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/grow-your-own-veggies-finding-the-right-plot/</guid>
      <description>Where to start You need to start by phoning your local council for lists of local allotments (societies/associations). Types of councils which might be linked to you may be;
 District Borough City Parish  An easy way to find which local council you are link to, go onto the government’s ‘Apply for an allotment  ’ page and type in your post code within the search facility. This will give you contact information for your local council.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grow Your Own Veggies: Plan for the Year</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/grow-your-own-veggies-plan-for-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 14:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/grow-your-own-veggies-plan-for-the-year/</guid>
      <description>At this stage of your grow your own veggies  quest, you should by now have;
 Found a plot Investigated what other neighbouring plot holders are planting Gained an understanding of how to prepare your plot (clearing/working) Gained an understanding of what/when to grow and how to rotate the crop Knowing what tools to use on the plot A deeper understanding regarding growing vegetables  Growing season starts in March, but you can do a lot of jobs beforehand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grow Your Own Veggies: Speak to Experienced Plot Holders</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/grow-your-own-veggies-speak-to-experienced-plot-holders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/grow-your-own-veggies-speak-to-experienced-plot-holders/</guid>
      <description>You have now made your choice, you have your plot and suddenly lots of questions start to flood into your mind;
 Where do I begin? What plants should I grow and when do I grow them? What gardening equipment do I need?  Where do I begin? How do I clear my plot? Hopefully your plot is not overgrown but 9 times out of 10 times it is, so clearing your plot is your first step.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
