<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Veggie Guide</title>
    <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Veggie Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veggieguide.co.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contribute</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/contribute/</guid>
      <description>Veggie Guide is a volunteer-run (no-one gets paid) project created to support those interested in plant-based food and ethical living.
We are always on the look-out for skilled writers (with experience) and other contributors who share our values. Please read our values below. If you still want to contribute, please drop us an email (email address in the footer) and include links to your previous works (where applicable).
While we very much care for animals and the environment, we do not judge those who think differently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Facts</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/food-facts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/food-facts/</guid>
      <description>Does Meat Consumption Lead to Obesity? Cross sectional research shows that vegetarians have considerably lower obesity rates&amp;hellip; But why? Researchers conducted a study of thousands of men and women to better understand the connection between meat consumption and obesity.
The results of the study were adjusted for many factors including exercise and total caloric intake. The study clearly demonstrated that if two people ate the same total calories each day for a year, but one regularly consumed meat and the other followed a vegetarian diet, the meat eater was likely to gain considerably more weight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This website (Veggie Guide) is provided as a volunteer-run project for the education and support of those interested in a plant-based diet and an environment-focused lifestyle. We do not intend to sell or distribute anyone&amp;rsquo;s data as this does not align to our goals.
The below information sets out how Veggie Guide uses and protects the data collected via our website.
When using this site, you are legally bound to the following privacy policy, so please read carefully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegan Business Directory</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/vegan-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/vegan-directory/</guid>
      <description>Our vegan directory is currently down.
The Veggie Guide Vegan Directory grew substantially over the last few years and, while it has served as a useful guide for those looking for places to eat and ethical businesses, some of the listings have become outdated; many of the businesses have changed their opening hours and some have closed.
For the sake of our readers, if we re-launch the Veggie Guide Vegan Directory, we want it to be as accurate and reliable as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elements</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:54:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/elements/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegan Dog Food Comparison and DIY Dog Food</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/vegan-dog-food-comparison-and-diy-dog-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 20:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/vegan-dog-food-comparison-and-diy-dog-food/</guid>
      <description>This simple guide details some of the best vegan dog food brands that are available, whilst also dipping into the world of DIY dog food, with two easy ‘at home’ recipes that will leave your canine companion&amp;rsquo;s taste buds tingling!
Commercial vegan dog food Below we have done our best to source the best vegan dog food brands and focused on brands which are environmentally conscious.
Disclaimer: We only recommend vegan/plant-based dog food where the owner can be sure that the food is complete in nutrition and that the dog is in good health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garlic &amp; Chive Veggie Burger Recipe</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/garlic-and-chive-veggie-burger-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 18:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/garlic-and-chive-veggie-burger-recipe/</guid>
      <description>While these garlic and chive burgers don&amp;rsquo;t share the meat-like texture or flavor that some may be familiar with, they have a taste that will please anyone and will leave you and your family feeling well-nurished and satisfied. Follow the recipe below for guaranteed results; and, when you are confident, feel free to innovate.
   You will need:  A food processor White kidney beans (2x tins) Butter beans (1x small tin) ½ chopped onion Crushed garlic (4 cloves) Chives (2 tbsp) 4-6 heaped tbsp gluten free flour A splash of vegetable oil Salt (⅓ tsp) Black pepper (½ tsp) Turmeric (⅓ tsp)  What to do:  Add the onion, garlic, black pepper, turmeric &amp;amp; salt into the food processor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Berry No-Bake (Vegan) Cheesecake</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/red-berry-no-bake-vegan-cheesecake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 18:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/red-berry-no-bake-vegan-cheesecake/</guid>
      <description>This no-bake “cheesecake” is guaranteed to impress all of your friends. Presentation can be tricky though, so make sure each layer is solid before adding the next!
Prep Time: 1-2 hours
Servings: 8
 ½ cup Brazil nuts (soaked overnight) 2 cups Pitted dates Cashew Coconut Layer 2 cups Cashews nuts (soaked overnight) 1 cup Coconut milk ¼ cup Coconut Oil Virgin ¼ cup Coconut Oil (Virgin) Berry Layer 1 cup Dark Chocolate Drops 1 cup Frozen cherries 1 cup Frozen raspberries ¼ cup Frozen strawberries 1 cup Pitted dates ¾ cup Coconut milk 70%+ Coconut extract  Instructions  Grease the pan with coconut oil and line with baking paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Practical Guide to Supporting Reforestation</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/a-practical-guide-to-supporting-reforestation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:42:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/a-practical-guide-to-supporting-reforestation/</guid>
      <description>While many are talking about deforestation and climate change, we don&amp;rsquo;t hear nearly enough about reforestation. This guide attests the importance of reforestation, tackles the controversy of flying abroad to volunteer and explains how we can all contribute.
What is the current state of forests globally? In the Amazon, it&amp;rsquo;s estimated that an area the size of a football field is cleared every minute  . One study  estimates that since the beginning of human civilisation we&amp;rsquo;ve reduced the number of trees on the planet by almost half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to Eating Vegan in Brighton</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/a-guide-to-eating-vegan-in-brighton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:39:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/a-guide-to-eating-vegan-in-brighton/</guid>
      <description>Known for its wacky street art, vintage shops and diversity, Brighton is claimed to be the ‘happiest and hippiest place to live in the UK’; it is no wonder that Brighton is one of the most vegan-friendly cities in the country. Below, we have compiled a list of vegan-friendly cafes and restaurants that you must try if you ever find yourself visiting ‘London by the sea’.
Wai Kika Moo Kau Found in the very heart of the North Laine, Wai Kika Moo Kau is a vegetarian/vegan café that has been serving delicious grub for nearly 30 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Amazing Vegans that will Inspire You</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/7-amazing-vegans-that-will-inspire-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:32:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/7-amazing-vegans-that-will-inspire-you/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps you’ve just survived a month of Veganuary  and realised you feel better than ever, and want a role model to ease you into your new diet. Or maybe you just want some inspiration and turn to Google for help.
Finding a list of vegan celebrities has never been easier: Enter the words in the search engine and you will quickly be supplied with a gallery of world-known faces such as Ellen Degeneres, Moby, Ellen Page and Ariana Grande.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Must-Visit Vegan-Friendly Coffee Shops in Leicester</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/3-must-visit-vegan-friendly-coffee-shops-in-leicester/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/3-must-visit-vegan-friendly-coffee-shops-in-leicester/</guid>
      <description>Believe it or not, Leicester is a vegan-foodie paradise. In fact, the term vegan was coined in Leicester by Donald Watson, who established the Vegan Society  in 1944 — the city&amp;rsquo;s vegan food scene has been on the rise ever since. Below, we explore some of our favourite vegan-friendly Leicester cafés for you to enjoy an aromatic coffee or a tasty plant-based piece of cake.
Coffee Ethic Coffee Ethic  is a vegan-friendly café located on Queens Road, the main street running through the vibrant Clarendon Park, an area popular amongst professionals, young families and students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Top Tips to Growing Veggies for Beginners</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/5-top-tips-to-growing-veggies-for-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/5-top-tips-to-growing-veggies-for-beginners/</guid>
      <description>Many would agree, supermarkets are convenient, but it’s nice to know where your food comes from and incredibly satisfying to know you grew it yourself. We asked John Bogumsky, a Leicester born allotment owner, for his top tips on how to get started growing your own vegetables.
I remember visiting my granddads allotment as a boy. To me and my sister it was a magical kingdom. It was full of home-made greenhouses and sheds made of old pallets and disused buildings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Vegan World Took to the Streets of Manchester for Vegan Education Day</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/go-vegan-world-took-to-the-streets-of-manchester-for-vegan-education-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/go-vegan-world-took-to-the-streets-of-manchester-for-vegan-education-day/</guid>
      <description>Saturday April 22nd was Vegan Education Day. 300 buses took Go Vegan World to the streets of Manchester to educate the public about animal rights and the hidden lives of animals in the food industry.****
With the help of vast digital screens, posters, 200 bathroom adverts and even jet washed pavement advertising across the city, the Go Vegan World   team were determined to make their message loud and clear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is a Vegan Diet as Sustainable as we Think?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/is-a-vegan-diet-as-sustainable-as-we-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/is-a-vegan-diet-as-sustainable-as-we-think/</guid>
      <description>Veganism is by definition  an animal rights movement, but the meteoric rise in plant-powered living isn’t down to animal lovers alone. 38%  of new vegans say that environmental concerns prompted the switch. But being vegan for environmental reasons can feel like a bit of a minefield, because it isn’t as straightforward as it seems.
What’s wrong with the vegan diet? If you care about the environment, it makes sense to think about food — which accounts for a quarter of total global emissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it okay for vegans to eat animals which died naturally?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/is-it-okay-for-vegans-to-eat-animals-which-died-naturally/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/is-it-okay-for-vegans-to-eat-animals-which-died-naturally/</guid>
      <description>This is a question I like to call a ‘vegan loophole’: a hypothetical and likely improbable question raised in order to challenge vegan ethics. Other loopholes include ‘if you were on a desert island…?’ and “What if you were living in Siberia…?”
What are we really asking here? Every vegan will have experienced some version of the ‘vegan loophole’ and will more than likely have asked something similar themselves before making the switch to veganism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegan Activities: The Ultimate Beginners Guide to Bouldering</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/vegan-activities-the-ultimate-beginners-guide-to-bouldering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/vegan-activities-the-ultimate-beginners-guide-to-bouldering/</guid>
      <description>Veganism is about more than food alone. Animal products are used frequently in clothing, and sports equipment, amongst other things. This post is part of a series of vegan activity guides covering how to get started and practical ways to avoid the use of animal products.
What is Bouldering? Bouldering is a form of rock climbing that does not use ropes, or harnesses and concentrates solely on movement on the rock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegan Hippo – A Small Vegan Café With a Big Conscience!</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/vegan-hippo--a-small-vegan-caf%C3%A9-with-a-big-conscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/vegan-hippo--a-small-vegan-caf%C3%A9-with-a-big-conscience/</guid>
      <description>Vegan Hippo is a vibrant and cosy café tucked away in Rupert Street in London’s Soho. The staff are friendly and look so youthful I wonder if there could be a more compelling argument for a plant-based diet.
The relaxed atmosphere is reminiscent of a community or student café, an increasingly rare sight in gentrified Soho, with brilliant surrealist animal paintings on the walls and a library of books to encourage long stays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Vegan Cosmetics Guaranteed to Make Your Friends Jealous</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/5-vegan-cosmetics-guaranteed-to-make-your-friends-jealous/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:26:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/5-vegan-cosmetics-guaranteed-to-make-your-friends-jealous/</guid>
      <description>The natural, alternative beauty market is growing fast – great news for ethical buyers who for too long have felt like they needed to compromise on the effectiveness of their cosmetics, in order to go cruelty free.
Unfortunately, many people are still unaware of the brilliant companies who successfully create great quality products that are ethically and sustainably produced, and that aren’t extortionately expensive.
So, here’s a selection of some of my favourite vegan and cruelty free beauty products – sure to impress vegans and mainstream beauty lovers alike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Avocado Spaghetti with Roasted Asparagus and Vine Tomatoes</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-avocado-spaghetti-with-roasted-asparagus-and-vine-tomatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:20:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-avocado-spaghetti-with-roasted-asparagus-and-vine-tomatoes/</guid>
      <description>A great weekday dinner when you don’t have much time to spare but want a filling and nutritious dinner. The spaghetti is served with English asparagus and tomatoes on the vine, however these can easily be replaced with other vegetables you have in your fridge — such as roasted broccoli, peppers or mushrooms.
This recipe serves 3
Ingredients:  300g wholemeal spaghetti Roughly 12-16 tomatoes on the vine, or 3 handfuls of cherry tomatoes 10-15 asparagus stems 1-2 tbsp olive oil 3 handfuls of spinach Sea salt  For the sauce:  1 large avocado 2 tbsp soya coconut yoghurt 200-300ml coconut milk Juice of 1/2 lemon 1 tbsp olive oil 2 garlic cloves  Method: Boil a pan of water and cook the spaghetti according to the instructions on the packet (this may vary).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Practical Tips for Eating Vegan on a Budget</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/five-practical-tips-for-eating-vegan-on-a-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:14:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/five-practical-tips-for-eating-vegan-on-a-budget/</guid>
      <description>It is unfortunate that in the Western world veganism often carries negative connotations. When I turned vegan, one of the first questions people would ask me is “How do you afford it?”. My response was a confused ‘quite easily, actually’.
The stereotype that living the vegan life is expensive needs to change; most plant food is actually very cost effective and long-lasting compared to the price of meat and dairy produce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Vegan&#39;s Guide to Hiking and Camping (Food and Equipment)</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/a-vegans-guide-to-hiking-and-camping-food-and-equipment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/a-vegans-guide-to-hiking-and-camping-food-and-equipment/</guid>
      <description>A major consideration for vegan hikers and campers is finding suitable food and ethical equipment and clothing. Though vegan food and clothing options are easier to locate than they were, sourcing quality gear that lends itself to a vegan lifestyle can be a challenge. In this post we cover both food items for camping and some of the more challenging hiking/camping gear.
Please note: we are not sponsored by any of the companies mentioned below, and we have not used affiliate links — all advice is impartial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Food Hacks That Make Veganism a Piece of Cake</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/5-food-hacks-that-make-veganism-a-piece-of-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:10:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/5-food-hacks-that-make-veganism-a-piece-of-cake/</guid>
      <description>With the right kitchen tools on hand and a pantry bustling with the perfect base ingredients, veganism boasts an abundance of possibilities! This guide will help you get to grips with some of the fundamentals you’ll need lurking around your kitchen and will begin to demonstrate how to make the most out of a plant based diet.
Invest in a Food Processor Pesto, hummus, cheesecake, nut milks and more: a food processor will become your best friend or your most sought after companion!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can a Plant-Based Diet Heal Digestive Problems?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/can-a-plant-based-diet-heal-digestive-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:10:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/can-a-plant-based-diet-heal-digestive-problems/</guid>
      <description>Back when I ate meat and dairy, I never thought anything of my subsequent indigestion and feeling ‘heavy’ for the rest of the day. I just thought it was genetic or that I ate too fast. I was obsessed with processed foods such as frozen pizzas or pepperamis, and I had a soft spot for cheese. Little did I know it was the main cause of my long-term stomach issues which began to become more prominent when I started college.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are We Ashamed To Be Vegan?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/are-we-ashamed-to-be-vegan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:06:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/are-we-ashamed-to-be-vegan/</guid>
      <description>Vegan, by definition, describes ‘a person who does not eat or use animal products’. But in reality, the word holds negative connotations. Whether you’re a lifelong vegan or devout meat eater, you’ve probably heard vegans variously referred to as hippies, tree-huggers, deranged, ill, pushy, anorexic, extreme or obnoxious. What the word doesn’t immediately suggest is compassionate, loving, kind, supportive or well intended.
Like many others who have chosen to adopt the vegan lifestyle, I have experienced first hand the backlash of the ‘vegan stereotype’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Going Vegan Mean Losing Your Friends?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/does-going-vegan-mean-losing-your-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 16:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/does-going-vegan-mean-losing-your-friends/</guid>
      <description>Being the only vegetarian or vegan amongst a group of friends will inevitably seem challenging at times. Suddenly meals out require more organization and prior research and unnecessary comments from a friend who’s overly-concerned with your ‘inadequate’ protein intake leave you feeling frustrated, not to mention the worry of being drawn into an emotive moral battle.
Of course there’s no real reason why any lifestyle choice should threaten a firm friendship, as long as you’re able to react to any potential misunderstandings, or unintentional insensitivity, with patience and an open mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plant-Based Milk Alternatives and Their Uses</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/plant-based-milk-alternatives-and-their-uses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 16:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/plant-based-milk-alternatives-and-their-uses/</guid>
      <description>Interest in plant-based milk alternatives is growing. In fact, a recent UK study estimated that the sales of plant-based milks are up by over 25% in the past 12 months — and for good reason: plant-based milks are healthy, delicious and far better for the environment. Thinking of making the switch? This handy guide will see you well on your way to discovering your favourite dairy-free alternative.
Which plant-based milks are most readily available?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grow Your Own Veggies: Read About Gardening</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/grow-your-own-veggies-read-about-gardening/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 14:38:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/grow-your-own-veggies-read-about-gardening/</guid>
      <description>To successfully grow vegetables and fruit, it is important to read about all aspects of gardening. Once you have started, you will gain valuable experience in both what to do and what not to do.
There are four main areas you could gain the necessary knowledge, these are: books, social media, websites, and magazines.
Books Books are a great source of knowledge as as the depth of information far outweighs other sources and each book mentioned below is highly regarded by experienced gardeners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six Lies Most People Believe about Meat and Dairy</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/six-lies-most-people-believe-about-meat-and-dairy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 14:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/six-lies-most-people-believe-about-meat-and-dairy/</guid>
      <description>This article aims to debunk some of the most persistent myths spouted by the meat and dairy brands, designed to deceive consumers into purchasing products which wreak havoc with their health, damage the environment and cause the suffering of billions of animals.
#1 Packaged meat is naturally red Most people don’t realise the extensive production process behind the neatly-packaged meat products they purchase from the supermarket. Meat contains a protein called myoglobin, which starts turning from red to brown once it is exposed to air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Banana Mango &amp; Tahini Smoothie Bowl</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-banana-mango-and-tahini-smoothie-bowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 13:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-banana-mango-and-tahini-smoothie-bowl/</guid>
      <description>This nutritious snack is delicious, especially on a lovely sunny morning, and will keep you filled up until lunchtime. Don’t like banana or mango? You can swap these with any other type of frozen fruit — adapt the toppings to your preference.
This recipe serves 1
Ingredients:  1 frozen banana (freeze in small chunks the night before) 80g frozen mango chunks (roughly one handful) 2 medjool dates with the pips removed 1 tbsp tahini 1 tbsp coconut soya yoghurt 200ml plant-based milk  Toppings (optional): 1 tbsp peanut butter, a handful of granola, a sprinkle of seeds and cacao nibs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Force Veganism on Your Kids!… What’s Your View?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/dont-force-veganism-on-your-kids-whats-your-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 13:10:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/dont-force-veganism-on-your-kids-whats-your-view/</guid>
      <description>I have always been firmly in the: “You shouldn’t force your beliefs onto your children”, camp and until recently, this even included veganism. However, a few things have begun to change my mind.
The power of conversation The other day I was discussing veganism with a friend who has been mostly vegetarian since childhood and has recently begun to embrace a more plant-based diet. This one conversation was the root of the change in my perception of raising vegan children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Vegan Brunch Places in London</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-best-vegan-brunch-places-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 11:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-best-vegan-brunch-places-in-london/</guid>
      <description>Once upon a time, being a vegan in London was a difficult task, as many restaurants offered limited menu options, or nothing at all. If we fast-forward to 2019, this is quite the contrary. With new vegan-friendly eateries popping up every year, it can be difficult to choose a place to eat. We have compiled a list of our favourite places for you to stop for brunch across London.
Pause — Spitalfields Pause Café in Spitalfields is dedicated to providing delicious and healthy food to their customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning a Successful Vegan Meetup</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/planning-a-successful-vegan-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/planning-a-successful-vegan-meetup/</guid>
      <description>If there’s one thing that almost all vegans love, it’s meeting up with other vegans for a chat, a meal or just a friendly reprieve from the non-vegan world at large. In this article we’ll touch briefly on various types of meetups and the websites available to organise them.
Potlucks, meals and action groups There are three types of meetups that feature most commonly in the vegan world: potlucks, restaurant gatherings, and activism actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Probiotics to a Vegan Diet</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/introducing-probiotics-to-a-vegan-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/introducing-probiotics-to-a-vegan-diet/</guid>
      <description>What do you think about when you hear the words ‘friendly bacteria’? Is it those tiny bottles of fermented milk, promising to beat the bloat? It’s true that dairy products like yoghurt or kefir are a common source of friendly bacteria — but, as a vegan, they don’t look so friendly after all. In this article, we take an in-depth look at probiotics and how vegans can introduce them into their diets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Creamy Vegan Mushroom Soup</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-creamy-vegan-mushroom-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 13:19:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-creamy-vegan-mushroom-soup/</guid>
      <description>This lovely mushroom soup is guaranteed to impress your friends, vegan or not! In this recipe, we have used nuts to develop a thick creamy texture that makes this vegan mushroom soup so much more satisfying. Enjoy this vegan mushroom soup as a healthy lunch or dinner — it&amp;rsquo;s so easy to make!
Ingredients:  1 pack of portobello mushrooms — sliced ½ cup boiled peanuts (can be substituted for pine nuts or cashews) 2 cups unsweetened oat milk (any plant milk can be used) 2 cups vegetable stock 1 shallot — finely diced 3 garlic cloves — chopped salt to taste ½ tsp black pepper juice of ½ lemon ½ tsp thyme ½ tsp oregano ½ tsp rosemary 1 tbsp olive oil fresh coriander (for the garnish)  Directions:  In a large deep pot, heat olive oil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview With a Vegan Musician – Ellis Slater</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/interview-with-a-vegan-musician--ellis-slater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 17:35:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/interview-with-a-vegan-musician--ellis-slater/</guid>
      <description>I met Ellis Slater and his Jack Russell, Molly, in the Blue Posts pub in Soho. We chatted over a couple of (vegan-friendly) beers and I polished off a delicious Korean-style curry, heavy enough on the red pepper paste to transport me briefly back to Busan, my once-home. But that’s enough about me. It’s time to meet Ellis – a vegan music-maker.
Making Music Photo credit: David Peter Coppin “I hate it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have a Happy Carnage-Free Easter</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/have-a-happy-carnage-free-easter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 14:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/have-a-happy-carnage-free-easter/</guid>
      <description>It’s now been several weeks since ‘Carnage’ debuted on BBC iPlayer and, so far, the reaction has been overwhelmingly positive. Both non-vegans and vegans have been flocking online to their blogs and twitter pages to sing its praises.
laughing and crying at #carnage  at the same time. hilarious, beautiful and eye-opening. time to entirely rethink my diet. @SimonAmstell  — dill funk (@qscats) March 26, 2017  Please watch Simon Amstell’s “Carnage”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is vegan “junk food” damaging our health and our reputation?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/is-vegan-junk-food-damaging-our-health-and-our-reputation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 14:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/is-vegan-junk-food-damaging-our-health-and-our-reputation/</guid>
      <description>In recent years there have been many vegan/plant-based conversions and much of that could be credited to an increased availability of meat and dairy alternatives. These days it is becoming common place to walk into a café and order a soya latte or step into a trendy pizza place and pick up a vegan cheese pizza.
I am pleased to see changes in the perception of veganism, but as a self-confessed “health nerd”, something seems seriously wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grow Your Own Veggies: Finding the Right Plot</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/grow-your-own-veggies-finding-the-right-plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/grow-your-own-veggies-finding-the-right-plot/</guid>
      <description>Where to start You need to start by phoning your local council for lists of local allotments (societies/associations). Types of councils which might be linked to you may be;
 District Borough City Parish  An easy way to find which local council you are link to, go onto the government’s ‘Apply for an allotment  ’ page and type in your post code within the search facility. This will give you contact information for your local council.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grow Your Own Veggies: Plan for the Year</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/grow-your-own-veggies-plan-for-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 14:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/grow-your-own-veggies-plan-for-the-year/</guid>
      <description>At this stage of your grow your own veggies  quest, you should by now have;
 Found a plot Investigated what other neighbouring plot holders are planting Gained an understanding of how to prepare your plot (clearing/working) Gained an understanding of what/when to grow and how to rotate the crop Knowing what tools to use on the plot A deeper understanding regarding growing vegetables  Growing season starts in March, but you can do a lot of jobs beforehand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Tips for Planning a Vegan Holiday</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/practical-tips-for-planning-a-vegan-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 12:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/practical-tips-for-planning-a-vegan-holiday/</guid>
      <description>With interest in vegan travel on the rise, increasingly, holiday makers are looking to pack their conscience with their flip-flops. If you’re not sure how to find good food, sustainable travel or animal-friendly activities, the following suggestions will help make your next holiday as gentle on our planet as it is delicious.
Choose a vegan-friendly destination First things first, you need to decide on where to go. Fortunately there are now a myriad of destinations catering for vegans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Sweet Potato and Chickpea Patties</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-sweet-potato-and-chickpea-patties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 08:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-sweet-potato-and-chickpea-patties/</guid>
      <description>A hearty, satisfying meal when you want something comforting and filling. These tasty sweet potato and chickpea patties are also great to have as left overs in a salad the next day. The nutritious patties are easy to make and require minimal preparation.
This recipe makes 3-4 patties.
Ingredients:  1 tin drained chickpeas 1 sweet potato, peeled, chopped into chunks and well boiled 1/2 chopped red onion 1 tsp oregano 1 tsp cumin 1/2 tsp garlic granules Pinch of salt and pepper Small handful of flour 1-2 tbsp olive oil  To serve:  Wholemeal buns Slices of avocado Spoonful of hummus Fresh spinach  Method:  Boil the sweet potato for around 15min (until soft inside — check with a fork) and drain, add to a mixing bowl and also add the drained chickpeas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Vegan World: Opening the Eyes and Hearts of the Public</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/go-vegan-world-opening-the-eyes-and-hearts-of-the-public/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/go-vegan-world-opening-the-eyes-and-hearts-of-the-public/</guid>
      <description>In recent months, something unusual has been happening across the UK. New posters depicting cows, pigs, and chickens have been appearing, but this time not as adverts for burgers, milkshakes and supermarkets. This is the world’s biggest animal rights campaign and is the creation of Go Vegan World, an educational organisation run by the founder of the Eden Farmed Animal Sanctuary.
An alternative approach to vegan outreach While the meat, dairy, and egg industries have traditionally advertised cosy images of animals delighted to be selling their own flesh and produce, Go Vegan World has turned the tables on this injustice, revealing to the consumer the individuals behind their choices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten Tips for New Vegans</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/ten-tips-for-new-vegans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/ten-tips-for-new-vegans/</guid>
      <description>So you have taken the leap to become vegan, or maybe you’re just curious. Well, you’re in the right place! These top vegan tips will help you hit the ground running.
1. Lots of things in your kitchen are already vegan Many of the foods you already own are likely vegan-friendly such as:
 Pasta Rice Most breads Peanut butter Jam Beans Coconut milk Soya sauce Herbs Vegetable stock cubes Couscous Fruit juice Tea and coffee and many more…  Have a look through your cupboards and you might be surprised!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Make Your Food Boring and Your Life Interesting&#39; — Andrew Taylor</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/make-your-food-boring-and-your-life-interesting--andrew-taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 17:15:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/make-your-food-boring-and-your-life-interesting--andrew-taylor/</guid>
      <description>The story of Andrew Taylor’s struggle with obesity starts as many stories of obesity do. It ends, however, with this Australian losing over 117 pounds (53.07 kg) within months, and helping thousands of others do the same. How? With potatoes.
 &amp;ldquo;I REALISED THAT MY BEHAVIOUR WITH FOOD MIRRORED THAT OF AN ALCOHOLIC WITH ALCOHOL&amp;rdquo;
 Overweight, Andrew was determined to diet, so he could return to a healthy lifestyle. As a vegan, he tried everything from green smoothies to healthy-meal alternatives like lentil bolognese without ever achieving durable success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grow Your Own Veggies: Speak to Experienced Plot Holders</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/grow-your-own-veggies-speak-to-experienced-plot-holders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/grow-your-own-veggies-speak-to-experienced-plot-holders/</guid>
      <description>You have now made your choice, you have your plot and suddenly lots of questions start to flood into your mind;
 Where do I begin? What plants should I grow and when do I grow them? What gardening equipment do I need?  Where do I begin? How do I clear my plot? Hopefully your plot is not overgrown but 9 times out of 10 times it is, so clearing your plot is your first step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Conscious Consumer</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-conscious-consumer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 11:06:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-conscious-consumer/</guid>
      <description>If you’re thinking of going vegan and you’ve made the choice to stop eating meat and other animal products, what about the clothes you buy? Perhaps you are ready for the next step – to go beyond just changing your diet and look at the other aspects of your life where you can reduce or eliminate the use of animal products.
This involves being a conscious consumer – knowing what brands are cruelty-free (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doubting Veganism? Maybe You Should!</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/doubting-veganism-maybe-you-should/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 18:40:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/doubting-veganism-maybe-you-should/</guid>
      <description>A vegan diet is sometimes regarded as ‘extreme’ and is often lumped with popular ‘fad’ diets. Cutting out animal products from your diet raises many questions from onlookers regarding your health.
Many people in the UK  (around 542,000 according to The Vegan Society  ) follow a vegan/plant-based diet. So, with numbers ever increasing, can plant-based eating be sustained and still provide everything we need to be healthy?
With new year campaigns such as Veganuary  , this is the month where interests peak and the amount of people following a plant-based diet takes a boost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Unexpected Side Effects of Going Vegan</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/8-unexpected-side-effects-of-going-vegan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 17:40:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/8-unexpected-side-effects-of-going-vegan/</guid>
      <description>All too often, following a vegan lifestyle is seen as restrictive. Undeniably, this is part of the truth. But what about the things you gain? Here are some of the positive (or at least, not negative) side effects that I’ve experienced since going vegan…
1 – My taste buds have evolved Things I used to hate (Yes, tofu, I’m looking at you) I now like. Actively. In my pre-vegan life I used to pick tofu out of dishes, now I add it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Top 7 Ways to be a Better Vegan have Nothing to do with Animals!</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-top-7-ways-to-be-a-better-vegan-have-nothing-to-do-with-animals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-top-7-ways-to-be-a-better-vegan-have-nothing-to-do-with-animals/</guid>
      <description>Avoiding animal products is not only the most important factor in being a vegan, it is the definition. But going plant-based and wearing hemp should not be where you complete your ethical evolution. Below are my top tips for being a better, more effective vegan:
1 – First rule of Veganism… “Don’t talk about Veganism!” OK, this one’s controversial I know, but I feel it needs addressing. It doesn’t take long before your friends and colleagues find out that you’ve gone vegan, so there is, arguably, no need to openly push it on people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Peacock: Nottingham’s First Vegan Pub Has Arrived!</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-peacock-nottinghams-first-vegan-pub-has-arrived/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-peacock-nottinghams-first-vegan-pub-has-arrived/</guid>
      <description>There’s been a lot of hype recently around Nottingham’s only pub to offer a 100% vegan food menu. Situated in the city centre of Nottingham, The Peacock made the decision to reopen after its refurbishment with the brave addition of a shiny new vegan kitchen. The pub had previously been a firm favourite with veggies and vegans for quite some time in the Nottingham area; offering most of its food with vegan equivalents meant that no one missed out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There’s No Real Difference Between Meat Eaters and Vegans</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/theres-no-real-difference-between-meat-eaters-and-vegans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/theres-no-real-difference-between-meat-eaters-and-vegans/</guid>
      <description>Here at Veggie Guide, we love people just as much as we love animals and we love meat eaters just as much as veggies and vegans. Why?
Because deep down we all have a lot in common.
Let me explain…
1 – We are weak! I used to eat meat (I ate meat for 24 years), then one day, when I no longer felt I needed it, I stopped.
Several years later The same happened for milk, some time after it was cheese, then finally eggs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veganism: The Fastest Growing Lifestyle Movement Ever!</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/veganism-the-fastest-growing-lifestyle-movement-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/veganism-the-fastest-growing-lifestyle-movement-ever/</guid>
      <description>There are now enough vegans in the UK to populate all of Sheffield, the 5th largest city in the country. This statistic was recently revealed by the Vegan Society’s latest study in which almost 10,000 people over the age of 15 were surveyed. The study indicates that there are currently over half a million, approximately 542,000, vegans living in Britain – that’s an incredible 260 percent increase on the 2006 study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of Leicester’s Vegan Market</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-rise-of-leicesters-vegan-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 12:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-rise-of-leicesters-vegan-market/</guid>
      <description>Walking through the alley between Gallowtree Gate and Market Square, I had a pleasant surprise. It was Sunday and raining but the market place was brimming with people. Not just people but vegan and open-minded people. The best kind. I’ll hold my hands up now and say I wasn’t expecting this. The idea of Leicester’s own vegan market being a big hit seemed bizarre to me, probably because as a relatively new vegan I didn’t know many vegans in Leicester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Results Are Record Breaking, But Veganuary Is Only Warming Up!</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-results-are-record-breaking-but-veganuary-is-only-warming-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-results-are-record-breaking-but-veganuary-is-only-warming-up/</guid>
      <description>Several years ago, few people had heard the word ‘Veganuary’. It was a weird portmanteau, difficult to pronounce and decipher. Fast-forward to January 2017 and a record breaking 59,500 people had signed up for the latest Veganuary pledge to go vegan for 31 days and now the word circulates throughout the mainstream press as well as the everyday vernacular.
  So, what is Veganuary? Veganuary is a charity dedicated to changing public attitudes toward veganism and aims to make the transition to a plant-based diet as easy, enjoyable, and delicious as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
