<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jess Roberts on Veggie Guide</title>
    <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/jess-roberts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jess Roberts on Veggie Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/jess-roberts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is it okay for vegans to eat animals which died naturally?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/is-it-okay-for-vegans-to-eat-animals-which-died-naturally/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/is-it-okay-for-vegans-to-eat-animals-which-died-naturally/</guid>
      <description>This is a question I like to call a ‘vegan loophole’: a hypothetical and likely improbable question raised in order to challenge vegan ethics. Other loopholes include ‘if you were on a desert island…?’ and “What if you were living in Siberia…?”
What are we really asking here? Every vegan will have experienced some version of the ‘vegan loophole’ and will more than likely have asked something similar themselves before making the switch to veganism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are We Ashamed To Be Vegan?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/are-we-ashamed-to-be-vegan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:06:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/are-we-ashamed-to-be-vegan/</guid>
      <description>Vegan, by definition, describes ‘a person who does not eat or use animal products’. But in reality, the word holds negative connotations. Whether you’re a lifelong vegan or devout meat eater, you’ve probably heard vegans variously referred to as hippies, tree-huggers, deranged, ill, pushy, anorexic, extreme or obnoxious. What the word doesn’t immediately suggest is compassionate, loving, kind, supportive or well intended.
Like many others who have chosen to adopt the vegan lifestyle, I have experienced first hand the backlash of the ‘vegan stereotype’.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
