<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vegan Places on Veggie Guide</title>
    <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/categories/vegan-places/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vegan Places on Veggie Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:39:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veggieguide.co.uk/categories/vegan-places/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to Eating Vegan in Brighton</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/a-guide-to-eating-vegan-in-brighton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:39:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/a-guide-to-eating-vegan-in-brighton/</guid>
      <description>Known for its wacky street art, vintage shops and diversity, Brighton is claimed to be the ‘happiest and hippiest place to live in the UK’; it is no wonder that Brighton is one of the most vegan-friendly cities in the country. Below, we have compiled a list of vegan-friendly cafes and restaurants that you must try if you ever find yourself visiting ‘London by the sea’.
Wai Kika Moo Kau Found in the very heart of the North Laine, Wai Kika Moo Kau is a vegetarian/vegan café that has been serving delicious grub for nearly 30 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Must-Visit Vegan-Friendly Coffee Shops in Leicester</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/3-must-visit-vegan-friendly-coffee-shops-in-leicester/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/3-must-visit-vegan-friendly-coffee-shops-in-leicester/</guid>
      <description>Believe it or not, Leicester is a vegan-foodie paradise. In fact, the term vegan was coined in Leicester by Donald Watson, who established the Vegan Society  in 1944 — the city&amp;rsquo;s vegan food scene has been on the rise ever since. Below, we explore some of our favourite vegan-friendly Leicester cafés for you to enjoy an aromatic coffee or a tasty plant-based piece of cake.
Coffee Ethic Coffee Ethic  is a vegan-friendly café located on Queens Road, the main street running through the vibrant Clarendon Park, an area popular amongst professionals, young families and students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegan Hippo – A Small Vegan Café With a Big Conscience!</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/vegan-hippo--a-small-vegan-caf%C3%A9-with-a-big-conscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/vegan-hippo--a-small-vegan-caf%C3%A9-with-a-big-conscience/</guid>
      <description>Vegan Hippo is a vibrant and cosy café tucked away in Rupert Street in London’s Soho. The staff are friendly and look so youthful I wonder if there could be a more compelling argument for a plant-based diet.
The relaxed atmosphere is reminiscent of a community or student café, an increasingly rare sight in gentrified Soho, with brilliant surrealist animal paintings on the walls and a library of books to encourage long stays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Vegan Brunch Places in London</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-best-vegan-brunch-places-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 11:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-best-vegan-brunch-places-in-london/</guid>
      <description>Once upon a time, being a vegan in London was a difficult task, as many restaurants offered limited menu options, or nothing at all. If we fast-forward to 2019, this is quite the contrary. With new vegan-friendly eateries popping up every year, it can be difficult to choose a place to eat. We have compiled a list of our favourite places for you to stop for brunch across London.
Pause — Spitalfields Pause Café in Spitalfields is dedicated to providing delicious and healthy food to their customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Peacock: Nottingham’s First Vegan Pub Has Arrived!</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-peacock-nottinghams-first-vegan-pub-has-arrived/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-peacock-nottinghams-first-vegan-pub-has-arrived/</guid>
      <description>There’s been a lot of hype recently around Nottingham’s only pub to offer a 100% vegan food menu. Situated in the city centre of Nottingham, The Peacock made the decision to reopen after its refurbishment with the brave addition of a shiny new vegan kitchen. The pub had previously been a firm favourite with veggies and vegans for quite some time in the Nottingham area; offering most of its food with vegan equivalents meant that no one missed out!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
