<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Charlotte Hooley on Veggie Guide</title>
    <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/charlotte-hooley/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Charlotte Hooley on Veggie Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 18:40:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/charlotte-hooley/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Doubting Veganism? Maybe You Should!</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/doubting-veganism-maybe-you-should/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 18:40:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/doubting-veganism-maybe-you-should/</guid>
      <description>A vegan diet is sometimes regarded as ‘extreme’ and is often lumped with popular ‘fad’ diets. Cutting out animal products from your diet raises many questions from onlookers regarding your health.
Many people in the UK  (around 542,000 according to The Vegan Society  ) follow a vegan/plant-based diet. So, with numbers ever increasing, can plant-based eating be sustained and still provide everything we need to be healthy?
With new year campaigns such as Veganuary  , this is the month where interests peak and the amount of people following a plant-based diet takes a boost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Peacock: Nottingham’s First Vegan Pub Has Arrived!</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-peacock-nottinghams-first-vegan-pub-has-arrived/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-peacock-nottinghams-first-vegan-pub-has-arrived/</guid>
      <description>There’s been a lot of hype recently around Nottingham’s only pub to offer a 100% vegan food menu. Situated in the city centre of Nottingham, The Peacock made the decision to reopen after its refurbishment with the brave addition of a shiny new vegan kitchen. The pub had previously been a firm favourite with veggies and vegans for quite some time in the Nottingham area; offering most of its food with vegan equivalents meant that no one missed out!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
