<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lifestyle on Veggie Guide</title>
    <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/categories/lifestyle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lifestyle on Veggie Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:26:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veggieguide.co.uk/categories/lifestyle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>5 Vegan Cosmetics Guaranteed to Make Your Friends Jealous</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/5-vegan-cosmetics-guaranteed-to-make-your-friends-jealous/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:26:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/5-vegan-cosmetics-guaranteed-to-make-your-friends-jealous/</guid>
      <description>The natural, alternative beauty market is growing fast – great news for ethical buyers who for too long have felt like they needed to compromise on the effectiveness of their cosmetics, in order to go cruelty free.
Unfortunately, many people are still unaware of the brilliant companies who successfully create great quality products that are ethically and sustainably produced, and that aren’t extortionately expensive.
So, here’s a selection of some of my favourite vegan and cruelty free beauty products – sure to impress vegans and mainstream beauty lovers alike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Practical Tips for Eating Vegan on a Budget</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/five-practical-tips-for-eating-vegan-on-a-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:14:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/five-practical-tips-for-eating-vegan-on-a-budget/</guid>
      <description>It is unfortunate that in the Western world veganism often carries negative connotations. When I turned vegan, one of the first questions people would ask me is “How do you afford it?”. My response was a confused ‘quite easily, actually’.
The stereotype that living the vegan life is expensive needs to change; most plant food is actually very cost effective and long-lasting compared to the price of meat and dairy produce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Going Vegan Mean Losing Your Friends?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/does-going-vegan-mean-losing-your-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 16:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/does-going-vegan-mean-losing-your-friends/</guid>
      <description>Being the only vegetarian or vegan amongst a group of friends will inevitably seem challenging at times. Suddenly meals out require more organization and prior research and unnecessary comments from a friend who’s overly-concerned with your ‘inadequate’ protein intake leave you feeling frustrated, not to mention the worry of being drawn into an emotive moral battle.
Of course there’s no real reason why any lifestyle choice should threaten a firm friendship, as long as you’re able to react to any potential misunderstandings, or unintentional insensitivity, with patience and an open mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview With a Vegan Musician – Ellis Slater</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/interview-with-a-vegan-musician--ellis-slater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 17:35:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/interview-with-a-vegan-musician--ellis-slater/</guid>
      <description>I met Ellis Slater and his Jack Russell, Molly, in the Blue Posts pub in Soho. We chatted over a couple of (vegan-friendly) beers and I polished off a delicious Korean-style curry, heavy enough on the red pepper paste to transport me briefly back to Busan, my once-home. But that’s enough about me. It’s time to meet Ellis – a vegan music-maker.
Making Music Photo credit: David Peter Coppin “I hate it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have a Happy Carnage-Free Easter</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/have-a-happy-carnage-free-easter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 14:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/have-a-happy-carnage-free-easter/</guid>
      <description>It’s now been several weeks since ‘Carnage’ debuted on BBC iPlayer and, so far, the reaction has been overwhelmingly positive. Both non-vegans and vegans have been flocking online to their blogs and twitter pages to sing its praises.
laughing and crying at #carnage  at the same time. hilarious, beautiful and eye-opening. time to entirely rethink my diet. @SimonAmstell  — dill funk (@qscats) March 26, 2017  Please watch Simon Amstell’s “Carnage”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Tips for Planning a Vegan Holiday</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/practical-tips-for-planning-a-vegan-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 12:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/practical-tips-for-planning-a-vegan-holiday/</guid>
      <description>With interest in vegan travel on the rise, increasingly, holiday makers are looking to pack their conscience with their flip-flops. If you’re not sure how to find good food, sustainable travel or animal-friendly activities, the following suggestions will help make your next holiday as gentle on our planet as it is delicious.
Choose a vegan-friendly destination First things first, you need to decide on where to go. Fortunately there are now a myriad of destinations catering for vegans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten Tips for New Vegans</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/ten-tips-for-new-vegans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/ten-tips-for-new-vegans/</guid>
      <description>So you have taken the leap to become vegan, or maybe you’re just curious. Well, you’re in the right place! These top vegan tips will help you hit the ground running.
1. Lots of things in your kitchen are already vegan Many of the foods you already own are likely vegan-friendly such as:
 Pasta Rice Most breads Peanut butter Jam Beans Coconut milk Soya sauce Herbs Vegetable stock cubes Couscous Fruit juice Tea and coffee and many more…  Have a look through your cupboards and you might be surprised!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Conscious Consumer</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-conscious-consumer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 11:06:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-conscious-consumer/</guid>
      <description>If you’re thinking of going vegan and you’ve made the choice to stop eating meat and other animal products, what about the clothes you buy? Perhaps you are ready for the next step – to go beyond just changing your diet and look at the other aspects of your life where you can reduce or eliminate the use of animal products.
This involves being a conscious consumer – knowing what brands are cruelty-free (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Unexpected Side Effects of Going Vegan</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/8-unexpected-side-effects-of-going-vegan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 17:40:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/8-unexpected-side-effects-of-going-vegan/</guid>
      <description>All too often, following a vegan lifestyle is seen as restrictive. Undeniably, this is part of the truth. But what about the things you gain? Here are some of the positive (or at least, not negative) side effects that I’ve experienced since going vegan…
1 – My taste buds have evolved Things I used to hate (Yes, tofu, I’m looking at you) I now like. Actively. In my pre-vegan life I used to pick tofu out of dishes, now I add it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
