<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>featured on Veggie Guide</title>
    <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/tags/featured/</link>
    <description>Recent content in featured on Veggie Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 20:29:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veggieguide.co.uk/tags/featured/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vegan Dog Food Comparison and DIY Dog Food</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/vegan-dog-food-comparison-and-diy-dog-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 20:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/vegan-dog-food-comparison-and-diy-dog-food/</guid>
      <description>This simple guide details some of the best vegan dog food brands that are available, whilst also dipping into the world of DIY dog food, with two easy ‘at home’ recipes that will leave your canine companion&amp;rsquo;s taste buds tingling!
Commercial vegan dog food Below we have done our best to source the best vegan dog food brands and focused on brands which are environmentally conscious.
Disclaimer: We only recommend vegan/plant-based dog food where the owner can be sure that the food is complete in nutrition and that the dog is in good health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegan Hippo – A Small Vegan Café With a Big Conscience!</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/vegan-hippo--a-small-vegan-caf%C3%A9-with-a-big-conscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/vegan-hippo--a-small-vegan-caf%C3%A9-with-a-big-conscience/</guid>
      <description>Vegan Hippo is a vibrant and cosy café tucked away in Rupert Street in London’s Soho. The staff are friendly and look so youthful I wonder if there could be a more compelling argument for a plant-based diet.
The relaxed atmosphere is reminiscent of a community or student café, an increasingly rare sight in gentrified Soho, with brilliant surrealist animal paintings on the walls and a library of books to encourage long stays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Practical Tips for Eating Vegan on a Budget</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/five-practical-tips-for-eating-vegan-on-a-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:14:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/five-practical-tips-for-eating-vegan-on-a-budget/</guid>
      <description>It is unfortunate that in the Western world veganism often carries negative connotations. When I turned vegan, one of the first questions people would ask me is “How do you afford it?”. My response was a confused ‘quite easily, actually’.
The stereotype that living the vegan life is expensive needs to change; most plant food is actually very cost effective and long-lasting compared to the price of meat and dairy produce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can a Plant-Based Diet Heal Digestive Problems?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/can-a-plant-based-diet-heal-digestive-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:10:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/can-a-plant-based-diet-heal-digestive-problems/</guid>
      <description>Back when I ate meat and dairy, I never thought anything of my subsequent indigestion and feeling ‘heavy’ for the rest of the day. I just thought it was genetic or that I ate too fast. I was obsessed with processed foods such as frozen pizzas or pepperamis, and I had a soft spot for cheese. Little did I know it was the main cause of my long-term stomach issues which began to become more prominent when I started college.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are We Ashamed To Be Vegan?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/are-we-ashamed-to-be-vegan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:06:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/are-we-ashamed-to-be-vegan/</guid>
      <description>Vegan, by definition, describes ‘a person who does not eat or use animal products’. But in reality, the word holds negative connotations. Whether you’re a lifelong vegan or devout meat eater, you’ve probably heard vegans variously referred to as hippies, tree-huggers, deranged, ill, pushy, anorexic, extreme or obnoxious. What the word doesn’t immediately suggest is compassionate, loving, kind, supportive or well intended.
Like many others who have chosen to adopt the vegan lifestyle, I have experienced first hand the backlash of the ‘vegan stereotype’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Going Vegan Mean Losing Your Friends?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/does-going-vegan-mean-losing-your-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 16:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/does-going-vegan-mean-losing-your-friends/</guid>
      <description>Being the only vegetarian or vegan amongst a group of friends will inevitably seem challenging at times. Suddenly meals out require more organization and prior research and unnecessary comments from a friend who’s overly-concerned with your ‘inadequate’ protein intake leave you feeling frustrated, not to mention the worry of being drawn into an emotive moral battle.
Of course there’s no real reason why any lifestyle choice should threaten a firm friendship, as long as you’re able to react to any potential misunderstandings, or unintentional insensitivity, with patience and an open mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plant-Based Milk Alternatives and Their Uses</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/plant-based-milk-alternatives-and-their-uses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 16:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/plant-based-milk-alternatives-and-their-uses/</guid>
      <description>Interest in plant-based milk alternatives is growing. In fact, a recent UK study estimated that the sales of plant-based milks are up by over 25% in the past 12 months — and for good reason: plant-based milks are healthy, delicious and far better for the environment. Thinking of making the switch? This handy guide will see you well on your way to discovering your favourite dairy-free alternative.
Which plant-based milks are most readily available?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Banana Mango &amp; Tahini Smoothie Bowl</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-banana-mango-and-tahini-smoothie-bowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 13:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-banana-mango-and-tahini-smoothie-bowl/</guid>
      <description>This nutritious snack is delicious, especially on a lovely sunny morning, and will keep you filled up until lunchtime. Don’t like banana or mango? You can swap these with any other type of frozen fruit — adapt the toppings to your preference.
This recipe serves 1
Ingredients:  1 frozen banana (freeze in small chunks the night before) 80g frozen mango chunks (roughly one handful) 2 medjool dates with the pips removed 1 tbsp tahini 1 tbsp coconut soya yoghurt 200ml plant-based milk  Toppings (optional): 1 tbsp peanut butter, a handful of granola, a sprinkle of seeds and cacao nibs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
