<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes on Veggie Guide</title>
    <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/categories/recipes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recipes on Veggie Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 18:29:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veggieguide.co.uk/categories/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Garlic &amp; Chive Veggie Burger Recipe</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/garlic-and-chive-veggie-burger-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 18:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/garlic-and-chive-veggie-burger-recipe/</guid>
      <description>While these garlic and chive burgers don&amp;rsquo;t share the meat-like texture or flavor that some may be familiar with, they have a taste that will please anyone and will leave you and your family feeling well-nurished and satisfied. Follow the recipe below for guaranteed results; and, when you are confident, feel free to innovate.
   You will need:  A food processor White kidney beans (2x tins) Butter beans (1x small tin) ½ chopped onion Crushed garlic (4 cloves) Chives (2 tbsp) 4-6 heaped tbsp gluten free flour A splash of vegetable oil Salt (⅓ tsp) Black pepper (½ tsp) Turmeric (⅓ tsp)  What to do:  Add the onion, garlic, black pepper, turmeric &amp;amp; salt into the food processor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Berry No-Bake (Vegan) Cheesecake</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/red-berry-no-bake-vegan-cheesecake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 18:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/red-berry-no-bake-vegan-cheesecake/</guid>
      <description>This no-bake “cheesecake” is guaranteed to impress all of your friends. Presentation can be tricky though, so make sure each layer is solid before adding the next!
Prep Time: 1-2 hours
Servings: 8
 ½ cup Brazil nuts (soaked overnight) 2 cups Pitted dates Cashew Coconut Layer 2 cups Cashews nuts (soaked overnight) 1 cup Coconut milk ¼ cup Coconut Oil Virgin ¼ cup Coconut Oil (Virgin) Berry Layer 1 cup Dark Chocolate Drops 1 cup Frozen cherries 1 cup Frozen raspberries ¼ cup Frozen strawberries 1 cup Pitted dates ¾ cup Coconut milk 70%+ Coconut extract  Instructions  Grease the pan with coconut oil and line with baking paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is a Vegan Diet as Sustainable as we Think?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/is-a-vegan-diet-as-sustainable-as-we-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/is-a-vegan-diet-as-sustainable-as-we-think/</guid>
      <description>Veganism is by definition  an animal rights movement, but the meteoric rise in plant-powered living isn’t down to animal lovers alone. 38%  of new vegans say that environmental concerns prompted the switch. But being vegan for environmental reasons can feel like a bit of a minefield, because it isn’t as straightforward as it seems.
What’s wrong with the vegan diet? If you care about the environment, it makes sense to think about food — which accounts for a quarter of total global emissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Avocado Spaghetti with Roasted Asparagus and Vine Tomatoes</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-avocado-spaghetti-with-roasted-asparagus-and-vine-tomatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:20:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-avocado-spaghetti-with-roasted-asparagus-and-vine-tomatoes/</guid>
      <description>A great weekday dinner when you don’t have much time to spare but want a filling and nutritious dinner. The spaghetti is served with English asparagus and tomatoes on the vine, however these can easily be replaced with other vegetables you have in your fridge — such as roasted broccoli, peppers or mushrooms.
This recipe serves 3
Ingredients:  300g wholemeal spaghetti Roughly 12-16 tomatoes on the vine, or 3 handfuls of cherry tomatoes 10-15 asparagus stems 1-2 tbsp olive oil 3 handfuls of spinach Sea salt  For the sauce:  1 large avocado 2 tbsp soya coconut yoghurt 200-300ml coconut milk Juice of 1/2 lemon 1 tbsp olive oil 2 garlic cloves  Method: Boil a pan of water and cook the spaghetti according to the instructions on the packet (this may vary).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Food Hacks That Make Veganism a Piece of Cake</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/5-food-hacks-that-make-veganism-a-piece-of-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:10:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/5-food-hacks-that-make-veganism-a-piece-of-cake/</guid>
      <description>With the right kitchen tools on hand and a pantry bustling with the perfect base ingredients, veganism boasts an abundance of possibilities! This guide will help you get to grips with some of the fundamentals you’ll need lurking around your kitchen and will begin to demonstrate how to make the most out of a plant based diet.
Invest in a Food Processor Pesto, hummus, cheesecake, nut milks and more: a food processor will become your best friend or your most sought after companion!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Banana Mango &amp; Tahini Smoothie Bowl</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-banana-mango-and-tahini-smoothie-bowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 13:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-banana-mango-and-tahini-smoothie-bowl/</guid>
      <description>This nutritious snack is delicious, especially on a lovely sunny morning, and will keep you filled up until lunchtime. Don’t like banana or mango? You can swap these with any other type of frozen fruit — adapt the toppings to your preference.
This recipe serves 1
Ingredients:  1 frozen banana (freeze in small chunks the night before) 80g frozen mango chunks (roughly one handful) 2 medjool dates with the pips removed 1 tbsp tahini 1 tbsp coconut soya yoghurt 200ml plant-based milk  Toppings (optional): 1 tbsp peanut butter, a handful of granola, a sprinkle of seeds and cacao nibs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Creamy Vegan Mushroom Soup</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-creamy-vegan-mushroom-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 13:19:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-creamy-vegan-mushroom-soup/</guid>
      <description>This lovely mushroom soup is guaranteed to impress your friends, vegan or not! In this recipe, we have used nuts to develop a thick creamy texture that makes this vegan mushroom soup so much more satisfying. Enjoy this vegan mushroom soup as a healthy lunch or dinner — it&amp;rsquo;s so easy to make!
Ingredients:  1 pack of portobello mushrooms — sliced ½ cup boiled peanuts (can be substituted for pine nuts or cashews) 2 cups unsweetened oat milk (any plant milk can be used) 2 cups vegetable stock 1 shallot — finely diced 3 garlic cloves — chopped salt to taste ½ tsp black pepper juice of ½ lemon ½ tsp thyme ½ tsp oregano ½ tsp rosemary 1 tbsp olive oil fresh coriander (for the garnish)  Directions:  In a large deep pot, heat olive oil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe: Sweet Potato and Chickpea Patties</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-sweet-potato-and-chickpea-patties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 08:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/recipe-sweet-potato-and-chickpea-patties/</guid>
      <description>A hearty, satisfying meal when you want something comforting and filling. These tasty sweet potato and chickpea patties are also great to have as left overs in a salad the next day. The nutritious patties are easy to make and require minimal preparation.
This recipe makes 3-4 patties.
Ingredients:  1 tin drained chickpeas 1 sweet potato, peeled, chopped into chunks and well boiled 1/2 chopped red onion 1 tsp oregano 1 tsp cumin 1/2 tsp garlic granules Pinch of salt and pepper Small handful of flour 1-2 tbsp olive oil  To serve:  Wholemeal buns Slices of avocado Spoonful of hummus Fresh spinach  Method:  Boil the sweet potato for around 15min (until soft inside — check with a fork) and drain, add to a mixing bowl and also add the drained chickpeas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
