<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Activities on Veggie Guide</title>
    <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/categories/activities/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Activities on Veggie Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veggieguide.co.uk/categories/activities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vegan Activities: The Ultimate Beginners Guide to Bouldering</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/vegan-activities-the-ultimate-beginners-guide-to-bouldering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/vegan-activities-the-ultimate-beginners-guide-to-bouldering/</guid>
      <description>Veganism is about more than food alone. Animal products are used frequently in clothing, and sports equipment, amongst other things. This post is part of a series of vegan activity guides covering how to get started and practical ways to avoid the use of animal products.
What is Bouldering? Bouldering is a form of rock climbing that does not use ropes, or harnesses and concentrates solely on movement on the rock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Vegan&#39;s Guide to Hiking and Camping (Food and Equipment)</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/a-vegans-guide-to-hiking-and-camping-food-and-equipment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/a-vegans-guide-to-hiking-and-camping-food-and-equipment/</guid>
      <description>A major consideration for vegan hikers and campers is finding suitable food and ethical equipment and clothing. Though vegan food and clothing options are easier to locate than they were, sourcing quality gear that lends itself to a vegan lifestyle can be a challenge. In this post we cover both food items for camping and some of the more challenging hiking/camping gear.
Please note: we are not sponsored by any of the companies mentioned below, and we have not used affiliate links — all advice is impartial.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
