<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Veggie Guide</title>
    <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Veggie Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veggieguide.co.uk/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contribute</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/contribute/</guid>
      <description>Veggie Guide is a volunteer-run (no-one gets paid) project created to support those interested in plant-based food and ethical living.
We are always on the look-out for skilled writers (with experience) and other contributors who share our values. Please read our values below. If you still want to contribute, please drop us an email (email address in the footer) and include links to your previous works (where applicable).
While we very much care for animals and the environment, we do not judge those who think differently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Facts</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/food-facts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/food-facts/</guid>
      <description>Does Meat Consumption Lead to Obesity? Cross sectional research shows that vegetarians have considerably lower obesity rates&amp;hellip; But why? Researchers conducted a study of thousands of men and women to better understand the connection between meat consumption and obesity.
The results of the study were adjusted for many factors including exercise and total caloric intake. The study clearly demonstrated that if two people ate the same total calories each day for a year, but one regularly consumed meat and the other followed a vegetarian diet, the meat eater was likely to gain considerably more weight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This website (Veggie Guide) is provided as a volunteer-run project for the education and support of those interested in a plant-based diet and an environment-focused lifestyle. We do not intend to sell or distribute anyone&amp;rsquo;s data as this does not align to our goals.
The below information sets out how Veggie Guide uses and protects the data collected via our website.
When using this site, you are legally bound to the following privacy policy, so please read carefully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegan Business Directory</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/vegan-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:55:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/vegan-directory/</guid>
      <description>Our vegan directory is currently down.
The Veggie Guide Vegan Directory grew substantially over the last few years and, while it has served as a useful guide for those looking for places to eat and ethical businesses, some of the listings have become outdated; many of the businesses have changed their opening hours and some have closed.
For the sake of our readers, if we re-launch the Veggie Guide Vegan Directory, we want it to be as accurate and reliable as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elements</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:54:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/elements/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
