<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iona Spence Dingle on Veggie Guide</title>
    <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/iona-spence-dingle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iona Spence Dingle on Veggie Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:26:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/iona-spence-dingle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>5 Vegan Cosmetics Guaranteed to Make Your Friends Jealous</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/5-vegan-cosmetics-guaranteed-to-make-your-friends-jealous/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:26:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/5-vegan-cosmetics-guaranteed-to-make-your-friends-jealous/</guid>
      <description>The natural, alternative beauty market is growing fast – great news for ethical buyers who for too long have felt like they needed to compromise on the effectiveness of their cosmetics, in order to go cruelty free.
Unfortunately, many people are still unaware of the brilliant companies who successfully create great quality products that are ethically and sustainably produced, and that aren’t extortionately expensive.
So, here’s a selection of some of my favourite vegan and cruelty free beauty products – sure to impress vegans and mainstream beauty lovers alike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Going Vegan Mean Losing Your Friends?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/does-going-vegan-mean-losing-your-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 16:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/does-going-vegan-mean-losing-your-friends/</guid>
      <description>Being the only vegetarian or vegan amongst a group of friends will inevitably seem challenging at times. Suddenly meals out require more organization and prior research and unnecessary comments from a friend who’s overly-concerned with your ‘inadequate’ protein intake leave you feeling frustrated, not to mention the worry of being drawn into an emotive moral battle.
Of course there’s no real reason why any lifestyle choice should threaten a firm friendship, as long as you’re able to react to any potential misunderstandings, or unintentional insensitivity, with patience and an open mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six Lies Most People Believe about Meat and Dairy</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/six-lies-most-people-believe-about-meat-and-dairy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 14:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/six-lies-most-people-believe-about-meat-and-dairy/</guid>
      <description>This article aims to debunk some of the most persistent myths spouted by the meat and dairy brands, designed to deceive consumers into purchasing products which wreak havoc with their health, damage the environment and cause the suffering of billions of animals.
#1 Packaged meat is naturally red Most people don’t realise the extensive production process behind the neatly-packaged meat products they purchase from the supermarket. Meat contains a protein called myoglobin, which starts turning from red to brown once it is exposed to air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veganism: The Fastest Growing Lifestyle Movement Ever!</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/veganism-the-fastest-growing-lifestyle-movement-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/veganism-the-fastest-growing-lifestyle-movement-ever/</guid>
      <description>There are now enough vegans in the UK to populate all of Sheffield, the 5th largest city in the country. This statistic was recently revealed by the Vegan Society’s latest study in which almost 10,000 people over the age of 15 were surveyed. The study indicates that there are currently over half a million, approximately 542,000, vegans living in Britain – that’s an incredible 260 percent increase on the 2006 study.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
