<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Munjeeta Sohal on Veggie Guide</title>
    <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/munjeeta-sohal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Munjeeta Sohal on Veggie Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 13:10:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/munjeeta-sohal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Force Veganism on Your Kids!… What’s Your View?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/dont-force-veganism-on-your-kids-whats-your-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 13:10:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/dont-force-veganism-on-your-kids-whats-your-view/</guid>
      <description>I have always been firmly in the: “You shouldn’t force your beliefs onto your children”, camp and until recently, this even included veganism. However, a few things have begun to change my mind.
The power of conversation The other day I was discussing veganism with a friend who has been mostly vegetarian since childhood and has recently begun to embrace a more plant-based diet. This one conversation was the root of the change in my perception of raising vegan children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview With a Vegan Musician – Ellis Slater</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/interview-with-a-vegan-musician--ellis-slater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 17:35:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/interview-with-a-vegan-musician--ellis-slater/</guid>
      <description>I met Ellis Slater and his Jack Russell, Molly, in the Blue Posts pub in Soho. We chatted over a couple of (vegan-friendly) beers and I polished off a delicious Korean-style curry, heavy enough on the red pepper paste to transport me briefly back to Busan, my once-home. But that’s enough about me. It’s time to meet Ellis – a vegan music-maker.
Making Music Photo credit: David Peter Coppin “I hate it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Unexpected Side Effects of Going Vegan</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/8-unexpected-side-effects-of-going-vegan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 17:40:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/8-unexpected-side-effects-of-going-vegan/</guid>
      <description>All too often, following a vegan lifestyle is seen as restrictive. Undeniably, this is part of the truth. But what about the things you gain? Here are some of the positive (or at least, not negative) side effects that I’ve experienced since going vegan…
1 – My taste buds have evolved Things I used to hate (Yes, tofu, I’m looking at you) I now like. Actively. In my pre-vegan life I used to pick tofu out of dishes, now I add it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
