<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tanya Szwarnowska on Veggie Guide</title>
    <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/tanya-szwarnowska/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tanya Szwarnowska on Veggie Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/tanya-szwarnowska/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Go Vegan World Took to the Streets of Manchester for Vegan Education Day</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/go-vegan-world-took-to-the-streets-of-manchester-for-vegan-education-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/go-vegan-world-took-to-the-streets-of-manchester-for-vegan-education-day/</guid>
      <description>Saturday April 22nd was Vegan Education Day. 300 buses took Go Vegan World to the streets of Manchester to educate the public about animal rights and the hidden lives of animals in the food industry.****
With the help of vast digital screens, posters, 200 bathroom adverts and even jet washed pavement advertising across the city, the Go Vegan World   team were determined to make their message loud and clear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegan Hippo – A Small Vegan Café With a Big Conscience!</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/vegan-hippo--a-small-vegan-caf%C3%A9-with-a-big-conscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/vegan-hippo--a-small-vegan-caf%C3%A9-with-a-big-conscience/</guid>
      <description>Vegan Hippo is a vibrant and cosy café tucked away in Rupert Street in London’s Soho. The staff are friendly and look so youthful I wonder if there could be a more compelling argument for a plant-based diet.
The relaxed atmosphere is reminiscent of a community or student café, an increasingly rare sight in gentrified Soho, with brilliant surrealist animal paintings on the walls and a library of books to encourage long stays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Vegan World: Opening the Eyes and Hearts of the Public</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/go-vegan-world-opening-the-eyes-and-hearts-of-the-public/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/go-vegan-world-opening-the-eyes-and-hearts-of-the-public/</guid>
      <description>In recent months, something unusual has been happening across the UK. New posters depicting cows, pigs, and chickens have been appearing, but this time not as adverts for burgers, milkshakes and supermarkets. This is the world’s biggest animal rights campaign and is the creation of Go Vegan World, an educational organisation run by the founder of the Eden Farmed Animal Sanctuary.
An alternative approach to vegan outreach While the meat, dairy, and egg industries have traditionally advertised cosy images of animals delighted to be selling their own flesh and produce, Go Vegan World has turned the tables on this injustice, revealing to the consumer the individuals behind their choices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Results Are Record Breaking, But Veganuary Is Only Warming Up!</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-results-are-record-breaking-but-veganuary-is-only-warming-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-results-are-record-breaking-but-veganuary-is-only-warming-up/</guid>
      <description>Several years ago, few people had heard the word ‘Veganuary’. It was a weird portmanteau, difficult to pronounce and decipher. Fast-forward to January 2017 and a record breaking 59,500 people had signed up for the latest Veganuary pledge to go vegan for 31 days and now the word circulates throughout the mainstream press as well as the everyday vernacular.
  So, what is Veganuary? Veganuary is a charity dedicated to changing public attitudes toward veganism and aims to make the transition to a plant-based diet as easy, enjoyable, and delicious as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
