<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mike Kirk on Veggie Guide</title>
    <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/mike-kirk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mike Kirk on Veggie Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 18:29:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/mike-kirk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Garlic &amp; Chive Veggie Burger Recipe</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/garlic-and-chive-veggie-burger-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 18:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/garlic-and-chive-veggie-burger-recipe/</guid>
      <description>While these garlic and chive burgers don&amp;rsquo;t share the meat-like texture or flavor that some may be familiar with, they have a taste that will please anyone and will leave you and your family feeling well-nurished and satisfied. Follow the recipe below for guaranteed results; and, when you are confident, feel free to innovate.
   You will need:  A food processor White kidney beans (2x tins) Butter beans (1x small tin) ½ chopped onion Crushed garlic (4 cloves) Chives (2 tbsp) 4-6 heaped tbsp gluten free flour A splash of vegetable oil Salt (⅓ tsp) Black pepper (½ tsp) Turmeric (⅓ tsp)  What to do:  Add the onion, garlic, black pepper, turmeric &amp;amp; salt into the food processor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Berry No-Bake (Vegan) Cheesecake</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/red-berry-no-bake-vegan-cheesecake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 18:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/red-berry-no-bake-vegan-cheesecake/</guid>
      <description>This no-bake “cheesecake” is guaranteed to impress all of your friends. Presentation can be tricky though, so make sure each layer is solid before adding the next!
Prep Time: 1-2 hours
Servings: 8
 ½ cup Brazil nuts (soaked overnight) 2 cups Pitted dates Cashew Coconut Layer 2 cups Cashews nuts (soaked overnight) 1 cup Coconut milk ¼ cup Coconut Oil Virgin ¼ cup Coconut Oil (Virgin) Berry Layer 1 cup Dark Chocolate Drops 1 cup Frozen cherries 1 cup Frozen raspberries ¼ cup Frozen strawberries 1 cup Pitted dates ¾ cup Coconut milk 70%+ Coconut extract  Instructions  Grease the pan with coconut oil and line with baking paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is vegan “junk food” damaging our health and our reputation?</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/is-vegan-junk-food-damaging-our-health-and-our-reputation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 14:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/is-vegan-junk-food-damaging-our-health-and-our-reputation/</guid>
      <description>In recent years there have been many vegan/plant-based conversions and much of that could be credited to an increased availability of meat and dairy alternatives. These days it is becoming common place to walk into a café and order a soya latte or step into a trendy pizza place and pick up a vegan cheese pizza.
I am pleased to see changes in the perception of veganism, but as a self-confessed “health nerd”, something seems seriously wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Top 7 Ways to be a Better Vegan have Nothing to do with Animals!</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-top-7-ways-to-be-a-better-vegan-have-nothing-to-do-with-animals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/the-top-7-ways-to-be-a-better-vegan-have-nothing-to-do-with-animals/</guid>
      <description>Avoiding animal products is not only the most important factor in being a vegan, it is the definition. But going plant-based and wearing hemp should not be where you complete your ethical evolution. Below are my top tips for being a better, more effective vegan:
1 – First rule of Veganism… “Don’t talk about Veganism!” OK, this one’s controversial I know, but I feel it needs addressing. It doesn’t take long before your friends and colleagues find out that you’ve gone vegan, so there is, arguably, no need to openly push it on people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There’s No Real Difference Between Meat Eaters and Vegans</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/theres-no-real-difference-between-meat-eaters-and-vegans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 17:29:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/theres-no-real-difference-between-meat-eaters-and-vegans/</guid>
      <description>Here at Veggie Guide, we love people just as much as we love animals and we love meat eaters just as much as veggies and vegans. Why?
Because deep down we all have a lot in common.
Let me explain…
1 – We are weak! I used to eat meat (I ate meat for 24 years), then one day, when I no longer felt I needed it, I stopped.
Several years later The same happened for milk, some time after it was cheese, then finally eggs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
