<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Annika Hagemann on Veggie Guide</title>
    <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/annika-hagemann/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Annika Hagemann on Veggie Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:32:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veggieguide.co.uk/authors/annika-hagemann/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>7 Amazing Vegans that will Inspire You</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/7-amazing-vegans-that-will-inspire-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 17:32:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/7-amazing-vegans-that-will-inspire-you/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps you’ve just survived a month of Veganuary  and realised you feel better than ever, and want a role model to ease you into your new diet. Or maybe you just want some inspiration and turn to Google for help.
Finding a list of vegan celebrities has never been easier: Enter the words in the search engine and you will quickly be supplied with a gallery of world-known faces such as Ellen Degeneres, Moby, Ellen Page and Ariana Grande.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Make Your Food Boring and Your Life Interesting&#39; — Andrew Taylor</title>
      <link>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/make-your-food-boring-and-your-life-interesting--andrew-taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 17:15:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://veggieguide.co.uk/blog/make-your-food-boring-and-your-life-interesting--andrew-taylor/</guid>
      <description>The story of Andrew Taylor’s struggle with obesity starts as many stories of obesity do. It ends, however, with this Australian losing over 117 pounds (53.07 kg) within months, and helping thousands of others do the same. How? With potatoes.
 &amp;ldquo;I REALISED THAT MY BEHAVIOUR WITH FOOD MIRRORED THAT OF AN ALCOHOLIC WITH ALCOHOL&amp;rdquo;
 Overweight, Andrew was determined to diet, so he could return to a healthy lifestyle. As a vegan, he tried everything from green smoothies to healthy-meal alternatives like lentil bolognese without ever achieving durable success.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
